Guide to the Charles L. Adams Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material, circa 1970-2000; Series VI; 3.42 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - Audio
    - Frank Waters Related, audiocassettes (Box 31)
      - Roundtable, Frank Waters, Milton, etc., Colorado Springs, copy, 1985 July 27; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395310)
      - Frank Waters Society, Denver, original, 1986 October 18; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395328)
      - Frank Waters Society, Denver, copy 2, 1986 October 18; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395336)
      - Seminar, RMMLA, (copy), 1979 October 20; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395344)
      - NPR, Taos Artists, 1982 July 25; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395351)
      - Stephen Paulus with QG, 1993 August 16; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395369)
      - Pike's Peak reading, Denver, copy, 1980 October 17; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395377)
      - Frank Waters Society with Frank Water present, Las Cruces, copy, undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395385)
      - Frank Waters Society, Spokane, original, 1987 October 17; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395393)
      - The Planetary Imperative, The Colorado College, Colorado Springs, original, 1985 July 28; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395401)
      - Roundtable, The Colorado College, Colorado Springs, 1985 July 20; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395419)
      - "Frank Waters in Henderson", undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395427)
      - Taos, copy 3, 1976 September 3; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395435)
      - MLA - LA, copy, 1982 December 29; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395443)
        Running time: 90 minutes.
      - RMMLA meeting, 1992 October; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395450)
      - The Planetary Imperative, The Colorado College, Colorado Springs, copy, 1985 July 28; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395468)
      - Frank Waters Society, Denver, 1997 October 17; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395476)
      - Pike's Peak reading, RMMLA, Denver, copy, 1980 October 17; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395484)
      - Seminar RMMLA, tape 2, copy, 1979 October 20; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395492)
      - Seminar RMMLA, tape 2, copy 2, 1979 October; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395500)
      - Interview with Cheryl Harvey, 1981 November 20; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395518)
      - Frank Waters meeting, RMMLA, El Paso, original, 1984 October 20; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395526)
      - Frank Waters Society, original, 1996 October 25; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395534)
      - Seminar, RMMLA, Denver, tape 2, copy, 1980 October 18; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395542)
      - Frank Waters Society meeting with Frank Waters presnet, Las Cruces, NM, original, 1988 October 21; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395559)
      - Interview with Cheryl Harvey, Las Vegas, copy 2, 1981 November 20; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395567)
      - Frank Waters Society, Salt Lake City, original, 1990 October 13; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395575)
      - Frank Waters Society, Spokane, 1987 October 17; 1; A note with the audiocassette details problems with motor noise and volume on side two. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395583)
      - "Otowi Crossing Opera: Act I", copy, undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395591)
      - "Otowi Crossing Opera: Act II", undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395609)
      - Singh on Yoga, original, 1981 February 25; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395617)
        A note from the desk of Charles L. Adams includes a list of terms, many of which relate to yoga. Some of the words include a meaning associated with them. The words are listed below.
        Mukti 1 Mioksha / Nirvana
        Jnana = knowledge
        Jiran - mukti = in [?] not of this world
        videh-mukti = [?]
        Samkhya - yoga
        Vedanta
        Nivritti - renuv[?]
        Pravritti - participation
        Dukha
        Dukkha - suffering
        Samudaya
        Nirodha
        Marga
        Samyaga
        Raga
        Tanha Pali
        Trishna
        Samradhi
        Han Shan
        Dharma - ought to do
        Karma
      - Adam, undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395625)
      - Joan Thorne interview, original, undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395633)
      - Thorne interview, copy, undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395658)
      - Charles L. Adams: "Roundtable", Colorado Springs, (copy), 1985 July 20; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395641)
      - Stephen Paulus with [?] Grigg, copy, undated; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395666)
      - Seminar: RMMLA, Denver, copy, tape 1 of 2, 1980 October 18; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091395674)
    - Other, audiocassettes (Box 32)
      Includes sound recordings that do not appear to be related to Frank Waters.
      - Joan Baez. Baptism, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091397993)
      - Cummings / Jeffers poetry, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398009)
      - "What if a Witch of a Wind", E. E. Cummings, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398017)
      - "Chansons Innocentes", Cummings, reviewer, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398025)
      - "Delta Autumn", Faulkner, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398033)
      - "Babylon Revisited", F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1990 September 7; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398041)
      - "Babylon", Fitzgerald, 1990 September 10; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398058)
      - "Babylon Revisited", Fitzgerald, Side I, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398066)
      - Hemingway, "The Gambler, the Nun and the Radio" / Classical Theory, Spenser and test, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398074)
      - "The Gambler, the Nun, and the Radio, Hemingway / Spenser, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398082)
      - "The Gambler, the Nun, and the Radio", Hemingway / Classical Society, Spenser, September 28; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398090)
      - Poetry of Houseman, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398108)
      - Jeffers reviewed, questions on end?, 1990 January 30; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398116)
      - Jeffers reviewed, 1990 April 1; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398124)
      - Jeffers reviewed, 1st frost, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398132)
      - Lawrence, February 26; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398140)
      - "The White Stocking", D. H. Lawrence / Spenser, 1998 September 29; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398157)
      - "The White Stocking", D. H. Lawrence, October 3; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398165)
      - "Artists in Uniform", Mary McCarthy, 1990 September 12; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398173)
      - "Mr. McGregor", Andrew Lytle / Classical Theory - Sociology, Marx, 1990 October 24; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398181)
      - "Artists in Uniform", September 14; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398199)
      - "The Artificial Nigger", Flannery O'Connor, 1990 November 7; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398207)
      - "The Artificial Nigger", Flannery O'Connor, lecture before exam / Reichert - Durkheim, suicide, 1990 November 15; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398215)
      - Reviews test "The Gambler" and "The White Stocking" / "A Losing Game", J. F. Powers and Hegel, 1990 October 10; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398223)
      - "A Sense of Shelter", John Updike, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398231)
      - "Defender of the Faith", Philip Roth, 1st lecture, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398249)
      - "Roman Fever", Edith Wharton (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990 September 15; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398256)
      - "Roman Fever", Edith Wharton, 2nd part (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1990 September 18; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398264)
      - Untitled, undated; 1; The audiotape reel is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398272)
      - John Gilchnese, copy I, 1977 November; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398280)
      - John Gilchnese, copy II, 1977 November; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398298)
      - SWAA 1, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398314)
      - SWAA 2, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398306)
      - Art Binder, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398322)
      - Joy Simmons I (copy), 1976 Spring; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398330)
      - Joy Simmons II (copy), 1976 Spring; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398348)
      - "The Artificial Nigger", 1990 November 7; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398355)
        A note with this audiocassette reads: "It's all in there if you need. Carefully pay attention and don't ignore any of it."
      - Aaron I (Manchester), 1976 October 23; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398363)
        A reading of "Aaron" in New Mexico.
      - Estes [Park], 1991 October 3; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398371)
      - Notes in Flight and Dylan II, Saturday, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398389)
      - "Pow-wow Magic", Charles Adam's copy, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398397)
      - Luar, original, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398405)
      - El Condor Pasa, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398413)
      - Langston Hughes, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398421)
      - Bob Clark, tape I, 1976 May 3; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398439)
      - Bob Clark, tape II, 1976 May 3; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398447)
      - Dictation, Stanford, (K Two=K-2) (Paricutín), undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398462)
      - Shasky (continued), undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398470)
      - Fechtor / Kohn, 1st part, undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398488)
      - Kohn 2nd cont., undated; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091398496)
      - Iron Maiden "Powerslave", undated; 1 (Box 32)
        This is a commercial audiocassette. It has not been digitized.
  - Video
    An item list of VHS cassettes can be found within the box.
    Restricted pending digital reformatting. Consult Access Services for information about reference copies.
    - "The Planetary Imperative" Colorado College, 1985 August; WAMSSS2615_0001; 1; 02:15:01; Sound is low. (Box 33, Item barcode 39002102300044)
    - "Penitentes-John Admondson"(?), undated; WAMSSS2615_0002; 1; 02:04:06 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002102300051)
    - "The Dark Wind", undated; WAMSSS2615_0003; 1; Tape was not digitized. (Box 33, Item barcode 39002102300069)
    - "The Earth is Alive: Sacred Lands as a Source of Balance @ Joan Price", undated; WAMSSS2615_0004; 1; 01:35:11 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002102300077)
    - "Frank Waters' The Colorado; Bill Fiero / Frank Waters Tape-Terry 1372", undated; WAMSSS2615_0005; 1; 00:58:08 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002102300085)
    - "Frank Waters, Henderson Nevada, videotape by Paul Lord", 1985 November 23; WAMSSS2615_0006; 1; 01:50:37 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002102300093)
- Oversize, 0.13; (1 box)
  - Magazines and clippings, 1976-1990s (Box 34, Folder 721)
- Computer media, 0.21; (1 box)
  - Computer Disks
    - volr1d, 2008-wa-25733-0001; 1 (Box 35)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - vol1d2, 2008-wa-25733-0002; 1 (Box 35)
    - FW SEMINAR AT FWPCA Feb 1996 Transcription of cassette, 2008-wa-25733-0003; 1 (Box 35)
    - FWPCA-96-Copy, 2008-wa-25733-0004; 1 (Box 35)
    - MS WORKS Matthias Schubnell Toward the Sixth World: Frank Waters and the New Environmental Consciousness 108 Fir San Antonio TX 78210 (502) 224 2823, 2008-wa-25733-0005; 1 (Box 35)
    - FW Changing Mountain Dialogues WordPerfect 5.1 IBM PS/2, 2008-wa-25733-0006; 1 (Box 35)
    - WATLAND WATASCII Gary Rogers, 2008-wa-25733-0007; 1 (Box 35)
    - ADAMS: Frank Waters Society Title Page: Studies, 2008-wa-25733-0008; 1 (Box 35)
    - WATERS.IBM, 2008-wa-25733-0009; 1 (Box 35)